dmc.com 2019-02-03

# Privacy policy

**DMC Intellectual Property, Data Protection, Privacy**

This site is the property of DMC sas.  Registered in the Trade and Companies Register of Mulhouse under number TI 510 469 406.  N° SIRET 501 469 406 0001. Head Office:

13 Rue de Pfastatt

68200 Mulhouse

France

Chairman and Chief Executive Officer: Dominique POILE, as legal representative of DMC sas.

In accordance with the provisions of 01/06/1978 Act, this site is the subject of a prior declaration to the National Commission for Computing and Liberty (CNIL), declaration number 1463954.

**Intellectual property**

Any reproduction or representation, total or partial, by any process whatsoever, of this site, logos, images, or any other media that may appear therein is prohibited without the express authorisation of DMC sas.

**Data Protection & Privacy**

As you interact with our website, our content, and our products, we collect some personal information to improve your customer experience.

You don’t have to give us this information, but if you don’t it’s unlikely you’ll be able to buy from our website or receive the best experience we can offer.

This table lists the main types of information we collect, and how we use it.

**How we use your name and contact details**  
  
---  
  
To deliver your orders to you

| 

We have to do this as part of our contract with you, and it’s impossible to deliver your order without these details.  
  
To send you service messages like delivery updates

| 

We send this type of message by email, by SMS and via messaging apps.  
  
Fraud prevention and detection

| 

We do this to keep us, and you, safe and secure.  
  
Showing you adverts as you browse the web

| 

So you can see our latest products and deals  
  
Finding out what products you, and other customers, like

| 

To ensure we are giving you the products you want and to help us find other customers like you  

**How we use your payment information**  
  
We don’t store credit card details, but we do use your CVV code (the 3 digits on the back of your card)  
  
Taking payment and giving refunds

| 

We have to do this as part of our contract with you, and it’s impossible to process your order without these details  
  
Fraud prevention and detection

| 

We do this to keep us, and you, safe and secure.  

**Your contact history with us**  
  
What you’ve said to us on email, phone, and chat or social media  
  
Providing customer service and support

| 

We have to do this as part of our contract with you, and it’s impossible to answer your queries without these details  
  
Staff training

| 

So that when you contact us, you get the best possible service  

**Your purchase history and saved items**  
  
What you’ve bought, added to your basket, or expressed an interest in  
  
Selling you our products

| 

We have to do this as part of our contract with you, and it’s impossible to process an order without these details  
  
Providing customer support and handling deliveries and returns

| 

We have to do this as part of our contract with you, and it’s impossible to process an order without these details  
  
Finding out what products you, and other customers, like

| 

To ensure we are giving you the products you want and to help us find other customers like you  

**Information about your device, and how you use our website**  
  
We collect your IP address, device type, your location (with permission), and anonymised data about how you browse our site.  
  
Improve our website, and set your language and currency preferences

| 

To give the best possible browsing experience  
  
To protect our website and your data

| 

We do this to keep us, and you, safe and secure.  

**Your responses to surveys and competitions**  
  
We run a variety of competitions, surveys, focus groups, and promotions. We need to collect some personal information to facilitate this.  
  
To run surveys, competitions and promotions

| 

We have to do this as part of our agreement with you, and it’s impossible to run the activities without these details  
  
**How we share your information:**

We do not, and will not, sell any of your personal data to any third party – including your name, address, email address or credit card information. We want to earn and maintain your trust, and we believe this is absolutely essential in order do that.

However, we share your data with the following categories of companies as an essential part of being able to provide our services to you, as set out in this statement:

    * Companies in the DMC Group, as sometimes different bits of our group are responsible for different activities (especially licensed ones)

    * Companies that do things to get your purchases to you, such as payment service providers, warehouses, order packers, and delivery companies

    * Professional service providers, such as marketing agencies, advertising partners and website hosts, who help us run our business

    * Credit reference agencies, law enforcement and fraud prevention agencies, so we can help tackle fraud

We may provide third parties with aggregated but anonymised information and analytics about our customers and, before we do so, we will make sure that it does not identify you.

**How we store your information**

We’ll hold on to your information for as long as you have your account, or as long as is needed to be able to provide the services to you, or (in the case of any contact you may have with our Customer Care team) for as long as is necessary to provide support-related reporting and trend analysis only.

If reasonably necessary or required to meet legal or regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce our terms and conditions, we may also keep hold of some of your information as required, even after you have closed your account or it is no longer needed to provide the services to you.

We don’t gather any more information than is necessary for fulfilling our obligations to you and providing a great customer experience, and we don’t hold on to your data for longer than is necessary.

We have a fulfilment centre in the USA, which we may use for processing orders from customers in the EU. The USA is not a country in respect of which there is a European Commission decision of adequacy, and we protect your privacy and your rights through the use of the European Commission’s standard data protection clauses. More information about these is available here [http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087)

**How we deliver marketing and advertising messages**

If you have said we can, we’ll send you marketing messages by email to keep you aware of our products, promotions and other content.

You can stop receiving marketing messages from us at any time by clicking on the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any email or by contacting our Customer Service team.

Once you do this, we will update your profile to ensure that you don’t receive further marketing messages.

Stopping marketing messages will not stop service communications (such as order updates or where you have expressed an interest in a product or activity).

We also engage in online advertising, also to keep you aware of what we’re up to and to help you see and find our products.

Like many companies, we target banners and ads to you when you are on other websites and apps. We do this using a variety of digital marketing networks and ad exchanges, and we use a range of advertising technologies like web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies, and mobile identifiers, as well as specific services offered by some sites and social networks, such as Facebook’s Custom Audience service.

The banners and ads you see will be based on anonymised and aggregated information we hold about you, or your previous use of our website.

**How we use cookies**

Like most websites, we use cookies when you visit our site. There are four main types of cookies – here’s how and why we use them.

(1) Site functionality cookies – these cookies allow you to navigate the site and use our features, such as “Add to Bag” and “Save for Later”.

(2) Site analytics cookies – these cookies allow us to measure and analyse how our customers use the site, to improve both its functionality and your shopping experience.

(3) Customer preference cookies – when you are browsing or shopping on DMC, these cookies will remember your preferences (like your language or location), so we can make your shopping experience as seamless as possible, and more personal to you.

(4) Targeting or advertising cookies – these cookies are used to deliver ads relevant to you. They also limit the number of times that you see an ad and help us measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.

By using our site, you agree to us placing these sorts of cookies on your device and accessing them when you visit the site in the future. If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, the “help” section in your browser should provide instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. 

**How we uphold your rights**

You have a lot of rights relating to your personal information:

    * The right to be informed about how your personal information is being used

    * The right to access the personal information we hold about you

    * The right to request the correction of inaccurate personal information we hold about you

    * The right to request that we delete your data, or stop processing it or collecting it, in some circumstances

    * The right to stop direct marketing messages, and to withdraw consent for other consent-based processing at any time

    * The right to request that we transfer or port elements of your data either to you or another service provider

    * The right to complain to your data protection regulator — in the UK, the Information Commissioner’s Office

You can exercise your rights by contacting us by email at contact-us@dmc.com or by mail at:

DMC Customer Service

5 Avenue of Switzerland

BP 40189

68314 ILLZACH Cedex.

If we make any significant change to this Privacy Policy, or any other policy that affects your rights, we will clearly communicate this to you via email, and on our website.
